<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIS on Chris&#39;s DataViz Gallery</title>
    <link>/dataviz/tags/gis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIS on Chris&#39;s DataViz Gallery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-2019 Christopher G. Prener</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/dataviz/tags/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Louis Metro Population Change</title>
      <link>/dataviz/project/stm-pop-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/project/stm-pop-change/</guid>
      <description>One of the questions the Post-Dispatch&amp;rsquo;s Janelle O&amp;rsquo;Day asked me during our conversation about the latest Census Bureau numbers for St. Louis yesterday had to do with where we&amp;rsquo;d expect to see declines and increases in population within counties.
For a quick recap, here are two plots summarizing county-level population change from 2010 to 2018 (using yesterday&amp;rsquo;s released estimates):
 We&amp;rsquo;ve seen continued declines in St. Louis City, St. Clair county, and Madison county in particular along with stagnant growth in St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Louis Neighborhood Change</title>
      <link>/dataviz/project/stl-pop-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/project/stl-pop-change/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the 2013-2017 5-year estimates from the U.S. Census Bureau&amp;rsquo;s American Community Survey, I wanted to get a sense of how St. Louis&amp;rsquo;s neighborhoods are changing in terms of population. These percentages compare the latest population estimates to the 2010 Decennial Census.
The largest estimated population growth is found in Downtown, Downtown West, the Central West End, The Grove, Lafayette Square, and Tower Grove East. Much of the rest of Midtown and South City saw either modest population increases or were stable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violent Crime in St. Louis, 2016-2017</title>
      <link>/dataviz/project/stl-belmar-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/project/stl-belmar-crime/</guid>
      <description>When Chief Belmar&amp;rsquo;s proposal for consolidating the City and County police departments was released to the media, one page happened to catch my eye. It had two kernel density maps of Part 1 crimes, which are defined by the FBI as all violent crimes (aggravated assault, rape, murder, and robbery) as well as property crimes (arson, burglary, larceny-theft, and motor vehicle theft).
As you can see, the map quality was poor and it lacked a legend (or even a description of what Part 1 crimes are).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>